The film. The classic musical comes to the big screen for the first time.
The Phantom of the Opera is a thriller, drama,
romance film directed by Joel Schumacher.
A young soprano becomes the obsession of a disfigured and murderous
musical genius who lives beneath the Paris Opera House.
The Phantom, played by Gerard Butler.
Christine, played by Emmy Rossum.
Raoul, played by Patrick Wilson.
Madame Giry, played by Miranda Richardson.
Carlotta, played by Minnie Driver.
Firmin, played by Ciarán Hinds.
The Phantom of the Opera is a 2004 musical romantic drama film based on Andrew Lloyd Webber's musical of
the same name, which in turn is based on Gaston Leroux's novel, Le Fantôme de l'Opéra.
Produced and co-written by Lloyd Webber and directed by Joel Schumacher, the film features an ensemble cast consisting of Gerard Butler as the titular character, with
Emmy Rossum, Patrick Wilson, Miranda Richardson, Minnie Driver, Simon Callow, Ciarán Hinds, Victor McGuire and Jennifer Ellison in supporting roles.
The film was announced in 1989, although production did not start until 2002
due to Lloyd Webber's divorce and Schumacher's busy career.
It was shot entirely at Pinewood Studios, with scenery
created with miniatures and computer graphics.
Rossum, Wilson and Driver had singing experience, but Butler had none
and was provided with music lessons prior to filming.
The Phantom of the Opera grossed $154.6 million worldwide.
It received mixed reviews from critics, with praise for the visuals and acting, particularly the performances of the lead
actors, but criticism towards the writing, direction and unnecessary deviations from the source material.
Despite its initial reception, the film received several awards and a trio of
Oscar nominations, as well as a positive reception from the audience.
The film explores themes of mask, dancing, paris, france,
based on novel or book, love triangle.
The tone is emotional and intense.